So inserting not at the end of a linked list is done by in sea, by creating a structured reference
had equal to null.
So I'm referencing the had is equal to no.
I will create a method called add at the end.
It took in parameter and valve and this that we will see how to use it.
So struct note I'm creating in you not look, I'm creating this note.
I will.
I reference this not equal to that, so the data is equal to their.
Of valid argument that they have passed to the method and the new next is equal to none.
I'm referencing their next of this newly created and nod to their knowledge because the last element
in the linked list were a reference to the not so if had equal equal to now had equal to new.
Not if the this means that if that the linked list is empty, then make that equal to then newly created
no else.
If there are elements, if there are many elements inside the linked list, then make make a struct,
not the last known equal to had.
And while the last note next does not equal to null, I need to insert class, not equal the last node
of next and last.
Not next.
Equal to new.
It's very simple.
Let's see how to use this function.
By adding it and you note that have a value 100 hundred, then not of the last to the last element of
the note.
If the first case, if we have no nodes inside the linked list, we have a link list, but we don't
have nodes inside it.
So it is the case where it had equal equal to none, then go and create a new note that contains one
hundred at the beginning and this is the end.
So the end, not end the the first node is the same.
If we have one note, OK?
And we are referencing to not this is the case.
But if we have many nodes.
OK.
We have like two knots.
I need to insert a new non equal equal to 200 by creating this is not the case because we don't we have
a linked list, but we have variables inside them.
We have nodes inside it.
OK, so this is the case of else.
I will create a last not equal to had.
This is the had and I will reference the last note to the head.
Why are the less not equal and the next to it does not equal to null, then go and replace it and make
the newly created one is equal referencing to the No.
This is maybe a maybe complex, maybe some difficulty in it, but it is very important to understand
this concept.
If that if there is no elements, then go and put that not.
As it so it would be the end and the start.
At the same time, if we have not inside the link, at least we used this truck.
No, we are replacing the last, not the reference of the last note and putting it in the last by switching
the last element in the previously created linked list to the reference of the newly created link at
list.
So we are replacing the now of the last element inside the link, replaced with the address of the and
the reference of the newly created a link of this or that note.
OK.
It's very simple.
Time complexity of this of and.
Because we are going through all the elements of the linked list in order to insert that note at the
end.
So think about having a linked list of 1000 1000 elements.
We are going to go through all the elements 1000 elements to insert at the end one note.
So it is all of an OK now let's see in setting, not at the end in Java.
We start by making the append because we are appending.
We are adding new nodes at the end.
Allocate the note and put in the node that data and set the next as no.
This is the three steps that we are going to make.
So I am creating a new node.
New, not equal.
New node.
Constructing new not.
And if the linked list is empty, then make the node as head.
This is the first case that we have seen in C.
And the step number four, we will continue by a new note next to none.
I am putting that first element to point to that, none because it is the endless.
If we have not, then go and execute step number five.
So else traverse still the last known traversing going and we are going like to print or to search and
or pass through or the atom.
And these will consume and cost of and because we are traversing all the elements, so not last equal
to head.
Why last dot next does not equal to now than the last equal last the next?
And the change then next of then last note to none because we need to change it.
The last known the previous to create link, at least to orient to that newly created list or newly
inserted not inside this list that builds to not.